the smoke has come to my valley
as the wildfires take their course it is
a reminder of how fragile
things can be
i must always be grateful for what i
have
this is crucial in order to live an
abundant life
despite the bitter smell of soot in the
air
there is work to be done autumn is fast
approaching
the trees are whispering to each other
time to prepare for the cold
and so must i
this video is going to be a little
different and that is because my options
for filming have been greatly limited
due to the smoke and poor air quality
instead i decided to simply answer some
questions that you have been asking
while i do that i thought i'd share some
insight in how i make early preparations
for fall
for example collecting pine cones to
later make
into fire starters
[Music]
a common question i get is where do you
live
so i live in the united states more
specifically
in northern washington state in little
valley in the okanogan county
within the town limits i believe there
are about 500 residents
there are no chain restaurants and
pretty much all the locals know each
other
out here you have to come to terms with
untamed nature
there are coyotes and cougars the
occasional moose and bear
many deer and wild rabbits i personally
enjoy
observing this side of nature but it is
definitely not for everyone
[Music]
another question i get is do i live
alone
also many ask am i lonely
i find the latter question to be rather
interesting because i get the impression
that there are many
lonely people all around the world and
many live in bustling cities
have friends and partners and yet still
feel isolated and alone
[Music]
i do not think loneliness or depression
depend on if you live with people
or not i view it as an emotion not a
location
or relationship status let me know what
your thoughts are on this and if you
agree or not
i find it to be very interesting
before i moved to the countryside i did
feel lonely
while i yearned to be nearer to my
family i realized more importantly
my interior life needed to be enriched
and my sense of purpose solidified
this sent me on a journey of self-growth
that led me here
now i spend time with my pets partner in
family every day
i'm half puerto rican and a strong sense
of hispanic culture
in my family has us always spending time
together
but i will add that my sense of
happiness and fullness comes from much
more than my relations
it is from an inner contentment that is
not reliant on external sources
it is an inner strength that i'm always
working on cultivating and growing
i also must add that i'm an introvert
and prefer quiet life
so socializing and meeting new people
isn't a priority for me
i realize that that may seem unusual to
those who are more social than i
but it is my nature
many of you also wanted to know how do i
afford to live here
so i won't go into the details but in
short i diversify my income
i work as a teacher at an alternative
preschool
on weekends i go to farmer's markets and
sell my art greeting cards and crafts
i recently opened an etsy shop and would
like to make at least a small success of
that someday as well
also my family is very close-knit
they're involved
in every step of my journey offering
needed support
wisdom and love
[Music]
some of you also wanted to know how i
get wi-fi reception
the short answer is i don't the hills
around my cottage make it difficult
but if i simply walk up a hill a ways or
visit my mother's house nearby
i can get reception i find ways to cope
with this by pre-downloading audiobooks
and shows and documentaries i'm
interested in watching
also it gives me time free of
distractions when i'm working on a new
art piece
in my case the inconvenience really
isn't that troublesome
[Music]
lastly a common question i get is what
are my pets names
so my rabbit's name is mr darcy
i have owned many rabbits in my life and
he is by far
the grumpiest he does not like waiting
for his food or staying indoors when
it's cold
however he does love head rubs and pets
so much
that he outright demands them by pulling
on your clothes
my dog's name is iger and he just turned
a year old he is very loyal
maybe too loyal he once ran over a mile
after my car when i left for work and
hurt his paws in the process
he's always happy we'll give you very
aggressive licks
and is still learning how to be
[Music]
civilized
anyway i hope answering these questions
was helpful to some of you
i will be sharing some new cottage
crafts next week in relation to autumn
preparations
thank you again for all the kind
comments on these videos
you may notice that i do my very best to
respond to each of you
and if i ever miss your comment by
mistake do let me know and i'm happy to
answer it
[Music]
you